[horse galloping]
♪
[ANNE]
Challe.
[LAFALLE]
What's wrong?
Are you cold?
Shh!
We're nearly there.
[CHALLE] All right,
we've come far enough.
Now, let Anne go.
She can't run away
from here alone
and you've got my wing
in your hands,
so there's no escaping.
As much as I would like
to prolong your torment,
it might make you so furious
that you would
never come back from it.
[Anne groans]
[Anne shivering]
Lafalle. She's freezing.
We need a fireplace.
Very well,
allow me to show you the way.
♪
[shuddering]
[sighs]
[ANNE]
Thank you, Challe.
That helps.
So our friends
and all our work.
D'you think they're safe?
And what about your wing?
[CHALLE]
It's fine.
Just forget all that for now.
I'm sure you're weary.
So rest.
You aren't working tomorrow.
Try to get some sleep.
♪
Stop it!
[whimpers]
Hm?
Flames are lovely,
don't you agree?
When I first saw humans
burning things
inside their houses.
I assumed that it was
only done for decoration.
But then I was surprised
to learn
that it was for survival.
They're so weak, aren't they?
Humans were originally
barbaric creatures.
Unsightly animals
with no wisdom
or strength to speak of.
So, naturally those filthy curs
admired us.
They adored us so much
that they began
to develop fairy-like forms
and slightly grow
more intelligent.
But they are nothing like us.
[CHALLE]
Get out.
[LAFALLE] I've prepared
a separate room for you.
It's not shabby and sparse
like this one.
After all, someone like you
belongs right next to me.
[CHALLE] You speak as though
you weren't squeezing my wing
in your hand before.
I would be glad to give it back
as long as you were prepared
to live alongside me
for the rest of your days.
There are warrior fairies here.
What purpose do they serve?
Follow me.
[LAFALLE]
The previous fairy king
tried to understand humans.
But the human king, Cedric,
instigated war against him.
That fact alone
ought to be proof
that fairies and humans
are fundamentally incompatible.
What is your point?
You do know it, don't you?
The name of the fairy king.
Riselva Cyril Sash.
Exactly the one
who gave us life.
[LAFALLE]
The owner of the sword
inlaid
with the precious stones.
Opal. Obsidian. Diamond.
In Riselva's Cyril Sash's eyes,
each of those gems
held great potential.
He hoped that one of them
would give birth
to the next fairy king.
You mean?
[EARL OF DOWNING] Anne Halford
has been abducted, you say?
Yes. I received word
from the Paige Workshop.
She was taken away by the fairy
who's been attacking
sugar artisans.
Others were injured, as well.
In light of this the festival's
a lost cause for them.
Then double the guards
at once.
[CHALLE]
The fairy king?
What makes you think
I'd believe that?
And even if it were true,
Riselva's sword was put
under the humans' protection.
No one wants the birth
of a new fairy king,
and you know that.
Well, no humans do.
[LAFALLE]
And yet, you and I were born.
I was gazed upon
by a moon eagle.
And you came to life
because of a young girl.
♪
However,
none of it was coincidence.
The fairy king had arranged
these destinies for us.
All these years later,
there's no sign
that our kin will be born
from the diamond.
In the end,
even though the fairy king
entrusted his legacy
to one of three,
only you and I were born.
And then,
after so much time apart,
I happened to find you.
We were fated to meet.
Don't you understand?
You and I are both so powerful.
Together we can set
all of the fairies free!
Then we can carry on
Riselva's will
and reclaim this kingdom
for our own kind!
Freedom. I see.
I refuse.
If that's what you want,
do it yourself.
Even if it is
what Riselva intended,
I still have no interest
in the fairy king.
[grunts]
[LAFALLE] Even after learning
the reason you were born?
That's for me to decide,
not Riselva.
This is because of that girl.
That little wretch.
To think that she has stolen
your heart so completely!
[grunts]
Don't you dare touch Anne!
I will cut you down!
I swear it!
[LAFALLE]
Are you sure you can?
You'll cut your wing
in the process.
If it means that you'll die,
then we'll die together.
You truly are devoted to her.
Very well.
In that case,
the next fairy king...
- will be me.
- [Challe grunts]
[LAFALLE]
But remember,
no matter how attached
you are to her,
she'll only bring
you both unhappiness.
[CHALLE]
What do you mean?
[LAFALLE]
You'll be fine.
Obsidian fairies
live long lives, after all.
So, you can seek
comfort from her
until the moment
her life runs out.
But think of Anne!
She will devote the entirety
of her life to caring for you
and leave no other mark
on this world.
When seeking someone
to share their lives,
humans are better off
with humans.
And it's only natural
for fairies
to spend their lives
with their own kind.
Mark my words,
you'll cause her nothing
but sorrow.
[horse galloping]
[KIETH] The Paige Workshop
was attacked?
[MARCUS] There's a message
from the Viscount.
The master's stand-in was hurt
and the Head of Artisans
was abducted,
along with the warrior fairy
who had traveled with her.
[Kieth gasps]
But that means...
Forgive me.
I need to go there!
- [MARCUS] Wait.
- [KIETH] Hm?
[MARCUS]
You know you won't be welcome.
Have you forgotten?
[KIETH]
No, but still. I have to!
[panting]
- I'll help you.
- You need to rest
until you're healed up.
You're hurt, too.
[grunts]
True.
Just don't push yourself
too hard.
Start with kneading.
[ORLAND]
Right.
[KIETH]
Please forgive the intrusion!
[panting]
[ELLIOTT] Kieth! Did you come
to check on our injuries?
Thanks, but we've got
everything covered here.
Mister Collins!
What are you doing?
I know that Anne
has just been abducted,
why are you working right now?
"Why?" Whatever do you mean?
Why are none of you
doing anything to help her?
You could search for her!
Or hunt down that fairy!
[stutters] Well,
we thought it was best to leave
all that to the Viscount.
That may be,
but why are the rest of you
still doing nothing?
[ELLIOTT]
But we are doing something.
No, you should be doing
something for Anne right now!
Are you a fool?
Why does it seem like
you don't care at all
about what could happen to her?
Is it because
she's not technically
an artisan
of the Paige Workshop?
[ELLIOTT] Anne isn't an artisan
How dare you say that?
Anne is our
Head of Artisans now!
You want us to do
something for her?
Do you think we wouldn't go
after her if we could, huh?
Listen, if Challe couldn't
defeat that monster,
then what could we do?
- [ORLAND] Elliott!
- The truth is,
we're all sugar artisans
and we're doing everything we
can possibly do for Anne here.
If she comes back to us, don't
you think she'll be unhappy
if we haven't made
any progress on our own?
Uh...
[ELLIOTT] That's why we're
continuing our work.
So tell me,
what should we be doing?
Huh! What's this?
Uh... Kieth's here?
That's enough fighting.
- He's going to collapse.
- Exactly!
The master's representative
should know better than that!
You're defiling a holy space.
[coughing]
[Elliott chuckles]
Sorry about that.
Really, I'm the one
who should be sorry.
I knew you'd all accepted Anne,
yet I still criticized
your actions.
I'm a traitor
to the Paige Workshop,
so I am in no position
to speak out.
[ELLIOTT]
Listen, Kieth.
The only one who sees it
that way is you.
Huh!
You're not the only reason
this workshop
started to go downhill.
A lot of things had
compounded all at once.
It just happened to line up
with you going to Radcliffe.
And even if you had come to us,
you wouldn't have gotten
special treatment.
Because that just isn't
the way Mr. Glen operates.
I think Master Radcliffe
cares a lot more
about those things
than we do.
That's for sure.
So, what did you
come here for, Kieth?
Well, I was worried
about Anne, so I thought...
No. That isn't all.
I realize now.
I always respected
the Paige Workshop
as the place
where my father did his work,
and all along, the only one
who concerned himself
with factions or preferential
treatment was me.
That's why I didn't understand
that you were sincerely doing
all of this for Anne's sake.
Till now I've been such a fool,
but no longer!
I am going to behave
differently!
To my father this place
was deeply meaningful.
That's why I wish
for the Paige Workshop
to carry on!
Would you allow me
to help you with the work?
If making sugar confections
will prove helpful
to Anne's cause, then I'd
like to lend you a hand!
Are you sure though?
I don't think your cranky
old headmaster would like it.
[chuckles]
I'm impressed, Mithril Lid Pod.
You're working hard as well!
Radcliffe will be fine.
Mr. Collins,
I'm ready to receive orders!
Welcome aboard.
[panting]
♪
[horses galloping]
I wonder how everyone is doing.
Poor Challe.
[LAFALLE]
Hello, Anne.
My darling little
silver sugar master.
What? Huh?
Wait, what's in there?
Sugar! I would like you
to make confections for me.
I still need to recover
all my strength
and there's no better
remedy for that
than the work
of a silver sugar master.
[ANNE]
How did you get that?
We had to work so hard
to refine it this year.
[LAFALLE]
Shall I tell you?
I refuse!
I want no part of it!
You won't help me?
You troublesome child.
But I'm not surprised.
You're as useless
as any other human.
You do realize
I'll have to kill you for that.
Well, it's no matter,
if you die
I'll just go fetch
some other pitiful human
from your little workshop.
No, wait!
Please don't hurt anyone else!
Huh.
In that case, who's going
to make the sugar confections?
[exhales]
[whimpers]
I'll make them for you.
Just leave the others alone.
[LAFALLE] You should have said
that to start with.
If you obey,
I'll take good care of you.
[ANNA]
Where is Challe right now?
[LAFALLE]
I believe he's washing himself.
If you had seen
the state that he was in,
I'm sure the sight
would've turned your stomach.
He's an impressive fairy.
I can see that
he's still hesitant,
but after that's gone,
I can only imagine
how incredible
his swordsmanship will be.
[ANNE]
What are you making him do?
[LAFALLE]
Oh, nothing too significant.
He's simply removing
those who'd stand in my way.
What do you mean?
Oh, are you worried?
Well, I suppose you do
love him, don't you?
To be honest,
if you care about him,
then it's better
if you leave him.
You'll be just fine.
You can enjoy having him
by your side for a while.
But as soon as you die,
he's going to be left
all alone again,
just as he was before.
In order to be happy,
humans and fairies
should stay amongst
their own kind.
If you truly want
what's best for Challe,
the answer is clear.
You'll let him live
with his fellow fairies
while you gracefully
step aside.
The way things are
you will cause him
nothing but sorrow.
[gasps]
[exhales]
[panting]
[ANNE]
Challe!
Where are you?
Huh!
[panting]
- In here?
- Hm?
[sighs]
[LUSUL]
Oh, I believe I know you!
You're the young lady
who gave me life!
- Huh?
- It's me!
Lusul El Min.
Don't you remember?
♪
You're from back then.
Huh.
What happened to your wing?
Oh, no, were you
captured by a human?
Actually, I removed my wing
and offered it
to Master Lafalle!
[ANNE]
Removed it?
You mean
you tore it off yourself?
[LUSUL] Oh, no,
I couldn't do it myself.
It would've been too painful.
Luckily, Master Lafalle
was kind enough
to do it for me!
And for everyone here!
We've all given
one of our wings to him.
To show proof of our loyalty!
[ANNE]
Your loyalty? But what for?
Why would anyone
pledge loyalty to him?
He's the new king
of the fairies,
so, of course, we would obey!
Under his leadership,
we'll claim our freedom!
He made a promise to fight
for the good of all fairies!
We serve him!
Claim your freedom?
[sobbing]
How cruel.
He sold you a lie.
It doesn't make any sense!
Why would he promise you
your freedom
and then take complete
control over you?
At that point, he's no
different than a human!
Oh, no.
This is only natural for us.
- After all, he's our new king.
- It's not natural!
He's not a king!
He's a fraud! [sobbing]
Why are you crying now?
Are you upset?
[ANNE]
No, I'm furious!
There's no reason
he would need your wings!
No king in the world
has the right to take something
that beautiful from you,
and a real king wouldn't!
[Anne crying]
[LUSUL]
Beautiful?
Beautiful.
[ANNE] How could you not see
how awful that is?
[LUSUL] Does that mean
you're crying for us?
Do you all feel that way?
Why is that?
- [sobbing]
- footsteps approaching]
Hm?
Oh, Challe.
Oh, you're the kind fairy
I met before!
This girl is upset,
but we're not
sure what the problem is.
Not a single one of you
understands why she's angry?
- Hm?
Lusul El Min. You either?
Huh...
I don't. I'm sorry.
[CHALLE]
Very well then. Let's go.
Wait a minute, please!
Can't you tell us why?
I'd like to know
what caused her tears!
This human girl
returned my wing.
And Lafalle stole it
back for himself.
Think about what that means.
[door creaking]
[CHALLE]
Are you all right?
It's just that,
I don't know the right thing
to do anymore.
♪